hey everyone it's Melanie ham welcome
back to my Channel today I'm going to
show you how to make this beanie this is
the same beanie tutorial from several
years back my how to crochet aini it's
totally beginner friendly that video
that video was at the beginning of my
crochet video tutorial career and I used
a dark yarn and I've been meaning to
redo this video for a long time now so
it's the same uh pattern as that video
but this one is just much better shot
you can see what I'm doing a lot easier
now that I know so much more about
making videos and putting them on
YouTube so I hope you enjoy this video
it's very beginner friendly and if you
have any questions on the yarn or the
hook that I use you can see the
description box underneath the video and
that will give you all the information
that you need so let's Jump Right In and
I'm going to show you how to make it I'm
going to start this hat with a magic
ring and I know a lot of times beginners
don't like to use magic rings they get
confused but really it's a better way to
start a hat so I'm going to go nice and
slow while I teach you this ma uh magic
ring part um and it once you get it it
really will make your hats so much
better and easier at the beginning okay
so just trust me on this beginners I
want you to hold your open end your free
end here and then we're going to take
our working yarn so the working yarn is
the yarn that's attached to your ball
okay so then we're going to take this
we're going to wrap it around two or
three fingers doesn't really matter
we're going to create a little
X okay so just follow along it's a
little cloudy so bear with me with the
lighting here then what you're going to
do is insert your hook into the
circle and we're going to pull up the
working yarn into a
loop
okay so just kind of hold everything
there and straighten out your yarn
and then make a just one little Stitch
yarn over pull it through okay there we
go that's really all there is to it okay
I know that it seems harder than it is
but um just go through that part of the
video a few times it takes a little bit
of practice it was hard for me at the
beginning too so don't feel um like
you're the only one cuz you're not so
then you can pull on the free end and
that will create a little bit smaller
Loop we don't need to work with a loop
so large
now what we're going to do is double
crochet 12 stitches right inside of our
Circle all right so a double
crochet is yarn over we're going to
insert it right into that
Circle yarn over pull through yarn over
two Loops yarn
over two Loops that's our double crochet
all
right so now we're going to do it again
yarn over insert it into the circle yarn
over pull
through yarn
over two Loops two Loops yarn over
insert into the circle yarn over pull
through yarn over two
Loops two
loops okay now I want you to keep doing
that until you have 12 double crochets
in your circle then I'll meet you back
here and show you what to do so let's
count here we've got 1 2 3 4 5 6
7 8 9 10
12 so the little Stitch that we made at
the beginning with our magic circle that
doesn't count count as a stitch it's
only our double crochets okay so we have
12 now what we're going to do is here's
our Stitch and here is this is the
Little V stitch this is the Stitch
that's at the top of the first double
crochet so we're going to
insert yarn over pull
through pull through the yarn on the
hook that's a slip Stitch now we can
pull on that free End and watch this is
why it's magic
wink there we go now our hat has a tiny
little Center that's what we're trying
to achieve with the magic
circle is a small Center so you can just
give that a good tug and now you don't
have any weird hole or anything at the
center okay chain
two
one 2
and then we are going to double crochet
two times in the first
Stitch okay so not the one we just came
out of because that doesn't count we're
going to go down over
here and we're going to double crochet
two times so we're going to insert it
this is the Little V shape that's what
you're looking for and you insert your
hook into both of those
threads Yar over pull through
Yar over
two two and then another double crochet
in the same Stitch that we just
did okay now we're going to go to the
next Stitch so you can see here's the
next one and then the next one and the
next one okay so the next Stitch is here
we're going to do one double
crochet all right and then two in the
same
Stitch and then
one all right and then
two so we're going to continue this
going all the way around
two double crochet then one two then one
two then
one so let's finish that up and I'll
meet you back at the beginning okay I
want to go over something really quick
this is my very high-tech Post-It note
um a lot of people get confused on this
especially beginners this is something
that you'll see in pattern so this is
two double crochet DC is the
abbreviation for the American term
double crochet uh for crochet
terminology this means that it's two
double crochet in the same Stitch double
crochet two means in two consecutive
stitches so two stitches next to one
another okay so this is something that
really makes people confused so I want
to make sure that we are going over that
because the next round really this is
the fourth
round Tech technically if you consider
magic circle round one I have all the
written instructions in the description
box that'll all be listed out but this
next round with the instructions always
confuses people so let's finish up this
round and this is important we're
finishing this one up we have our two
our one two and one we need to have a
total of 18 stitches okay so make sure
you have 18
two in the
same
Stitch and then there's another Stitch
right here okay I want you to do your
last Stitch it should be a single double
crochet like one of
them okay now you have
18 I double checked myself so I know
that there's 18 and then we are going to
slip stitch in the top of the first
double crochet so here it is you see
that little V stitch this is our turning
chain so this is remember we did chain
one one two at the beginning so this is
one two then here's the top of our first
double crochet so this is where we're
slip
stitching yarn
over pull through so that's our slip
stitch okay now we're going to do the
same thing
again one two and then we are going to
do two double crochet double crochet to
so not stitching in the chain we came
out of we've already sort of used that
up so we are going to double
crochet
two okay and then
one and then in the next one over
okay so next to each
other so two double crochet double
crochet two we're going to do that same
thing going all the way around two in
the same
Stitch whoops
okay and then we'll go double crochet
double crochet next to each other
consecutive stitches all right so go
ahead and do that finish this round I'll
meet you back here okay now you're going
to notice it's going to start turning
into a hat shape you should have 24
stitches okay so make sure a little
trick to know if you're on the right
track is if you're ending with your
single stitches so not where we're
increasing so when we do two stitches in
one stitch as in a hat that's where
we're increasing we're making it larger
in order for us to fit ahead right so
then the two consecutive double crochets
are should be what you're finishing the
round with because we started with the
double crochet if that makes sense if
that's confusing just count them and
make sure you have 24 okay
so double
crochet and then this is going to be the
foundation for our pattern you will
notice in the written instructions and I
recommend that you print out the written
instructions and follow along with them
while you're making your hat okay so
here's again our turning
chain so this was one two this is the
top of that double crochet stitch so
that is where we are double that is
where we are Slip stitching excuse me
yarn over yarn over that's our slip
stitch and then we're going to continue
same exact thing chain two but now
instead of double two double crochet
crochet two so we did two then one two
then one now we're doing two then two
two then two now it's two then three two
then three so that's basically the
pattern that we're going to be doing
we're going to be increasing the hat for
several more
rounds okay so again don't go into this
first Stitch with that we already came
out of we already used it up yarn over
double
crochet same Stitch
okay that's one we're going to go two
three okay three
consecutive double
crochets two one two 3 then we'll go two
in the same Stitch 1 2 3 all right so
continue that going all the way
around okay so same thing here's our two
one two three we know that's our little
hint that I didn't miscount anywhere
along the way but you need to
have 30
stitches okay 30 stitches at the end of
this
round same exact thing don't do the
Turning chain we're going to slip stitch
into the top of that initial double
crochet okay now the exact same thing
chain
two we're going to do two double crochet
but instead of three it'll be four so
it'll be double crochet 2 1 2 3 4 2 1 2
3 4 2 1 2 3 4 Etc all right print out
the written instructions they will be
linked for you in the description box
and you are going to go ahead and keep
doing that all those rounds up until you
get to two double crochet cret double
crochet six okay so it'll be four this
round is four five and then six which
would be a total of 48 stitches again
print out those written instructions
that way you have all of those numbers
right in front of you so you can follow
along with that once you hit this round
48 stitches we I will meet you back up
here and then we will be done increasing
and we'll go ahead and just be standard
double crocheting all the way around
till we reach our desired hat size but
for now
go ahead and finish out the next couple
of rounds until you have finished two
double crochet double crochet six which
should equal 48 stitches all right so we
have completed our rounds just to catch
you up here one two one 2 3 4 five six
okay so remember we've got this little
guy right at the base of our chain two
that we can't forget about all right so
double crochet in there to finish out
our 48 stitches and our final round of
increasing all right so then we're going
to slip stitch to the top of that first
double crochet just like we were doing
before insert your hook yarn over pull
through pull through okay now kind of
give yourself a little slack and one of
the things that I recommend as you're
making this hat you can see how it sort
of is a little bit conical a little bit
there's we don't want it to be too cone
shaped
so I sort of just fit it to my own head
you want to flatten it down and kind of
spread it
out right on your head kind of like I
just did here and see this is how it
should look so periodically shape it to
your
head uh even if it's not for you it just
will kind of help with the overall shape
of the Hat as you continue stitching
around now what we are doing is we are
going to double crochet in each Stitch
going all the way around no more
increasing we've already made our hat
the proper size for an
adult so we are going to chain two
still and then we are going to you know
skip this first one exactly like we did
before double crochet but only one in
each Stitch going all the way
around so here's
one and we're basically going to do that
to the very
end until you reach your desired size
and I will have a chart Linked In the
description box for popular
sizes and kind of a a good little
reference point so do one double crochet
in each Stitch going all the way around
and then when I come back here I'll show
you kind of how to do this
transition okay here we are at the
transition I shaped it to my head again
so we have a nice kind of bow shape head
shape that we're working with
now don't forget we have two more
stitches here one two we can forget this
guy otherwise it'll make a weird kind of
Gap so we don't want
that so we're going to finish
out this round and then we're basically
just going to continue like we did
before and just ignore that chain two Al
together okay
so just ignore this chain two from the
the beginning and we're going to yarn
over and just place a double crochet
right in the top of that Stitch where we
would
normally uh slip stitch
into and then just kind of make sure you
give you give that a little bit of a tug
because we don't want this to be too
large of a gap we want it to sort of be
inconspicuous and then you can continue
going all the way around if this if the
Gap is a little bit too large and you're
having trouble with this then slip
stitch chain two just like we been doing
and and completing the hat that way is
absolutely
fine this just makes it so you don't
have to do that going
around and by the end of your hat it
creates a nice kind of
transition so you can see that
here all right so go ahead and one
double
crochet all the way
around all right so we are at about 7
and 1/2 in
you can
[Music]
see about there so now I'm going
to it's a little bit longer than
that so now I'm going to do my single
crochet edging similar to this hat so
I'm going to do two rounds of single
crochet and then we'll do a slip stitch
Edge that's optional you don't have to
you can finish it off just like this if
you want to but it does sort of create a
finished look on your hat so here we are
you can see our little transition over
here and then everything has kind of
spiraled down you can sort of see how
that's worked itself
out and I'm going to just start single
crocheting so right here at this join
this you know will be at the back of
your head so you won't see any of these
Transitions and we're going to single
crochet and a single crochet is insert
your hook yarn over pull through yarn
over pull through both Loops all right
so it's a little bit smaller Stitch and
we're still going to do the same thing
where we are doing that in each Stitch
going all the way
around all right so here's kind of how
it's looking so I want you to do that
all the way around and then I'll show
you what it looks like at this
transition piece so finish going all the
way around your hat if you have trouble
seeing the differences in your stitches
definitely use a stitch
marker um but you can see right here
this is the initial single crochet where
we started so we want to finish up you
know close to that so all of our
transitions are in one spot now what I'm
going to do is slip stitch around the
entire edge of my hat and that's going
to really create a nice finished look
and as slip stitch is insert your hook
yarn over pull through yarn over that
Loop like pull through that loop on the
hook okay so one more time
insert the hook yarn over pull
through and continue through the loop on
your
hook and then we're going to do that in
every Stitch going around and I'll show
you sort of the look that it creates you
can also just do this at the edge of
your double crochet if you don't want to
continue with the single crochet little
Edge and you can see right here it kind
of creates this little this nice little
edging versus this Edge so you can see
this versus this so that's what the
little slip stitch Edge does so if you
want to do that continue doing that all
the way around and I'll show you how to
fasten off all right so here we
are this is where we started over here
so when we finish it
up going to
continue basically all the way to the
end
we start here you can kind of see where
that Stitch kind of comes onto the side
of the
Hat that's and and again if you need a
stitch marker then please use a little
stitch marker or a safety pin that will
work also bobby pin hair clip I mean you
could really improvise with that all
right so here's our last
one so you can see there we can kind of
create that that little
Edge so then we'll do is trim our yarn
leave yourself 6 to 8 inches of
tail because then we're going to weave
it in so what we'll do is we'll just
pull that yarn through give it a
tug and now get a yarn needle this is a
yarn needle it's metal or plastic and
has a large eye like
this and we will weave in
so this is the outside of the
hat so what we'll do
is sew the end in on the inside of the
Hat we're going to do the same thing
with that initial magic ring tail so we
got to make sure don't forget to do that
one too in the center inside of the hat
and to weave these in we want to sort of
go back and forth and make sure that
it's all hidden that way if you want to
wash the hat everything is going to be
secure and there'll be no unraveling so
I kind of like to go One Direction and
then kind of go
up back up the opposite direction that
way that's kind of going back and forth
there's a little bit of a
[Music]
zigzag and once you have done a good job
of weaving in the
tail and you feel confident that it's
secure and you trim
it and don't forget to do the same thing
with the inside of our hat can give it a
good little pull and weave in this Tail
as well all right that's it what did you
guys think of this hat double crochet
beginner friendly we've got a nice
finished edge here with our single
crochet border and our slip stitch
edging here is how you crochet a beanie
[Music]